Fernando Kawano

kawano.fer@qmail.com - linkedin.com/in/fernandokawano

SUMMARY

I'm a software developer with over 10 years of experience working in the IT industry, specializing in web development using JavaScript's modern framework, React. I'm also skilled with Sharepoint writing and modifying code to build applications and sites for clients based on their needs and requirements. I worked from startups to big companies, developing several systems with variant complexity.

I always try to meet and exceed expectations, and I enjoy working collaboratively with people involved in the project to achieve the goals. I'm passionate about continuous learning and keeping my skills up-to-date with the latest JavaScript technologies.

EXPERIENCE

Front-end Software Engineer

Kenect - 10/2021 - 01/2024

Salt Lake City, Utah, US · Remote

- As a Frontend Software Engineer at Kenect, I played a crucial role in creating a
 user-friendly platform that made it easier to create backend team integrations with our
 partner's system. I developed this platform using Kenect Design Systems. I worked closely
 with my manager and the backend team to ensure smooth integration by creating and
 using endpoints.
- The main technologies used in this project were React, Redux-Saga, Context API, styled-components, Firebase, REST API, and GIT.

Sharepoint/React Engineer

VEXPRO Business IT - 12/2016 - 10/2021

Curitiba, Brazil · On-site/Remote

- Developed an extensive system for an agribusiness cooperative with React and Redux, creating reusable components to use among pages
- Developed corporate portals and systems for SharePoint Classic and Modern sites, creating custom modules and components for meeting client's specific needs
- Customized Material-UI theme according to the designer requirements
- Created an ECM system to scan documents to be managed on the system
- Developed an entire service desk, where the company could open issues, new features, or projects to be set. It was developed using Angular and Bootstrap, while the layout, front-end, and back-end structure were created using SharePoint. There was the use of workflows to send emails to notify.

- Worked on the development of custom modules and components in SharePoint Portals
- Created an ECM (Enterprise Content Management system) using Sharepoint SPfx, and React with Typescript. This ECM was built to manage over 1 million digital documents and set specific permissions to groups and users.

Full Stack Engineer

PRx Consultoria em Seguros - 03/2020 - 07/2020

Curitiba, Paraná, Brazil · Remote

- For this project, the request was to create a platform where PRx partners could view announcements, access a list of partner brokers, and be able to input and visualize their goals, displaying region-specific graphs. Platform administrators would have the ability to manage all the information.
- To accomplish this, I utilized React, redux-thunk, and Material-ui for the frontend development. I also used the MySQL server of the website to store the information and developed the backend using NestJs and NodeJs.

Mobile Developer

Moments.Surf - 10/2016 - 12/2016

Curitiba, Paraná, Brazil · On-site

- Development in Ionic/cordova, NodeJs, Amazon WebServices. Bootstrap, AngularJs 1.0, and integration with Parse and MongoDb.
- Bug fixes and development improvements in the application and application startup support.

Front-end Developer

Big Brain - 04/2016 - 08/2016

Curitiba, Paraná, Brazil · On-site

- Developed web portals and a management system, using JavaScript, jQuery, and Bootstrap to create responsible pages.
- Created a C# web API to make data integration between SharePoint and databases

Fullstack ASP .NET and Angular.JS

Positivo Informática - 08/2015 - 02/2016

Curitiba, Paraná, Brazil · On-site

- Developed educational projects using C#, .NET, Angular, and SQL Server
- Worked on the development of educational activities and games using HTML5

Frontend Developer

Positivo Informática - 12/2012 - 08/2015

Curitiba, Paraná, Brazil · On-site

Development of educational content in HTML5, for desktop and mobile.

Java Developer

Franciscana de Ensino Senhor Bom Jesus Sep 2010 - Nov 2012 \cdot 2 yrs 3 mos Curitiba, Paraná, Brazil \cdot On-site

Developing improvements in Java systems using SQL Server 2008.

PROJECTS

Game Falcão Prateado

September 2014 - December 2014

The game Falcão Prateado is a project developed in two months using Unity2D. In these two months we had to develop all interface, conception and learn to use Unity2d from zero. In four months we had more than 3.000 downloads without use paid advertisement.

Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/GameFalcaoPrateado

EDUCATION

Postgraduate, Mobile Applications, and Cloud Computing Universidade Positivo • 2015

4, ba. Information System

Universidade Positivo • 2011

CERTIFICATIONS

Exam 480: Programming in HTML5 with JavaScript and CSS3

Microsoft • 2019

Tools & Technologies: Adobe XD, Agile Methodologies, AngularJS, API development, Back-end development, Cloud computing, Debugging, ECMAScript, Firebase, Front-End Development, Java, JavaScript, Jira Service Desk, Nodejs, React.js, Redux.js, Responsive Web Design, REST APIs, Scrum, Sharepoint Framework (SPFx), Software Development, Styled-components, TypeScript, Unit Testing, Version Control, Web Development, Zeplin